[upbeat ukulele music]
[欢快的尤克里里音乐]
* *
**
French narrator:
Ah, behold the migration
法语解说员：
啊，看迁移
of the majestic clams.
[clams cawing]
雄伟的蛤蜊。
[蛤蜊叫声]
In search of warmer climates,
and plentiful food.
为了寻找温暖的气候，
和充足的食物。
[cawing continues]
[叫声继续]
- [whistles]
- [口哨]
narrator: The clams
have begun to signal each other.
叙述者：蛤蜊
已经开始互相发出信号。
A hospitable location
has been found.
热情好客的地点
已被发现。
The grace they exhibit
is truly--
他们所展现的优雅
确实是——
Zut alors!
Zut alors！
Dive! Dive!
潜水！潜水！
[clams cawing]
[蛤蜊叫声]
[whimsical music]
[异想天开的音乐]
- Wow!
- 哇！
- What are you doing, SpongeBob?
- [surprised yelling]
- 海绵宝宝，你在做什么？
- [惊讶的叫喊]
I'm just checking out
the beautiful clams.
我刚刚查看
美丽的蛤蜊。
Did you know
it's migration season?
你知道吗
现在是迁徙季节吗？
- Yeah, I know.
- 是的，我知道。
bawling]
嚎叫]
I don't know!
我不知道！
I lied to you!
[whimpering]
我骗了你！
[呜咽]
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- Patrick, it's okay!
- 帕特里克，没关系！
- [whimpers]
Okay.
- [呜咽]
好的。
- Do you need to blow your nose?
- 你需要擤鼻涕吗？
- [burbling blows]
- [颤抖的打击]
You're a good friend.
你是个好朋友。
- [giggling]
- [咯咯笑]
- So can I see the clams?
- 那我可以看看蛤蜊吗？
- Sure! Here, use these.
- 当然！在这里，使用这些。
- Thanks!
- 谢谢！
* *
**
Hey!
嘿！
[panicked straining]
[惊慌失措]
[choking]
- Patrick!
[窒息]
- 帕特里克！
[both grunting]
[两人都咕哝着]
- Phew!
- 唷！
Maybe we better
just use our eyes.
也许我们更好
只要用我们的眼睛。
- Good idea.
- 好主意。
[grunts]
[咕哝]
* *
**
[clam chirping]
- Ooh!
[蛤蜊鸣叫]
- 哦！
Clams are so pretty!
蛤蜊真漂亮！
- Just look at all those
majestic species!
- 看看所有这些
雄伟的物种！
There's the Soft Shell Clam.
这里有软壳蛤。
- [yawns]
Hmm.
- [哈欠]
嗯。
- The Hard Shell Clam.
- 硬壳蛤。
[clangs]
[叮当声]
The Giant Clam.
[brakes screeching]
巨蛤。
[刹车声]
- Come on! Get out of the way!
- 快点！走开!
[growls]
[munches]
[咆哮]
[咀嚼]
- Even a Razor Clam.
- 甚至是蛏子。
- Just clean me up, as usual.
- 像往常一样，把我清理干净。
[clam whirring]
[蛤蜊呼呼]
- [bewildered laughter]
I'm beautiful!
- [困惑的笑声]
我很美丽！
- Aw, I wish the clams
were closer to us
- 哦，我希望有蛤蜊
离我们更近
so we could get a better look.
这样我们就可以看得更清楚。
[both burbling]
Wait! I know!
[两者都在咕噜咕噜地响]
等等！我知道！
They're always hungry
when they migrate!
他们总是很饿
当他们迁移时！
* *
**
[happy humming]
[快乐哼哼]
* *
**
- [slurping]
- [发出声音]
- [happy humming]
- [快乐的哼唱]
- [slurping]
- [gasps]
- [发出声音]
- [喘气]
Patrick, the patties
are for the clams!
帕特里克，馅饼
是为了蛤蜊！
- I'm sorry, SpongeBob.
- 对不起，海绵宝宝。
[munches]
[咀嚼]
[slurps]
- Patrick!
[啜饮]
- 帕特里克！
- What? I'm not perfect.
- 什么？我并不完美。
* *
**
But I am full.
但我已经饱了。
Nap time!
午睡时间！
[snoring]
[打鼾]
- Aw.
[chuckles]
- 噢。
[笑声]
* *
**
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
[clams squawking]
[蛤蜊嘎嘎叫]
* *
**
It's working!
它正在工作！
[gasping]
[喘气]
Huh?
啊？
- [snoring]
[cute chirping]
- [打鼾]
[可爱的叽叽喳喳声]
* *
**
- Isn't that beautiful?
- 那不是很漂亮吗？
* *
**
-  What is in a Squidward?
- 章鱼哥里有什么？
A Squidward
by any other name would--
章鱼哥
任何其他名字都会——
[loud squawking]
[大声尖叫]
[groans]
Uh. Where was I?
[呻吟]
呃。我当时在哪儿？
Ah, yes!
啊，是的！
A Squidward, dancing fast,
乌贼王，舞姿飞快，
moving like grace it--
像恩典一样移动——
[loud squawking]
Oh, that is it!
[大声尖叫]
哦，就是这样！
Will you clams clam up!
蛤蜊你会不会蛤蜊！
[disgusted groan]
[厌恶的呻吟]
[clams chirping]
[蛤蜊鸣叫]
Oh, look at what the clams
are doing to my beautiful home!
哦，看看蛤蜊是什么
正在为我美丽的家园做事！
SpongeBob, will you stop
feeding those clams!
海绵宝宝，你能停下来吗
喂那些蛤蜊！
- Why, Squidward?
- 为什么，章鱼哥？
- Because they're making a me--
- 因为他们正在塑造一个我--
Agh! Stop!
啊啊！停止！
- Maybe I have been
feeding these clams too much.
-也许我曾经是
喂这些蛤蜊太多了。
[Squidward groaning]
[章鱼哥的呻吟声]
[sobs]
I'll never be clean again!
[抽泣]
我再也不会干净了！
* *
**
- * Walking to work
ain't too shabby! *
- * 步行去上班
是不是太破旧了！ *
* 'Cause I'll be whipping up
a Krabby Patty!
*因为我会兴奋起来
蟹肉饼！
[clams cawing]
Huh?
[蛤蜊叫声]
啊？
[cawing stops]
[叫声停止]
[cawing continues]
[叫声继续]
Go on home, you clams!
回家吧，蛤蜊们！
I have to go to work now.
我现在得去上班了。
Go on. Go home.
继续。回家吧。
I don't have anymore
Krabby Patties for you.
我没有了
蟹肉饼给你。
You need to find your own food.
你需要找到自己的食物。
* *
**
Okay then. I'll just--
那么好吧。我就——
[panting]
[clams cawing]
[气喘吁吁]
[蛤蜊叫声]
[giggles]
Oh! Follow the leader!
[咯咯笑]
哦！听从领队！
* *
**
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
Bye! I'll see you
crazy clams later.
再见！我会见到你
稍后疯狂蛤蜊。
[clam caws]
[蛤叫声]
* *
**
- Hey, that's mine!
- 嘿，那是我的！
[growling]
[咆哮]
[screaming]
- What are you doing?
[尖叫]
- 你在做什么？
You know it's not nice
to steal people's food!
你知道这不好
偷别人的食物！
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
Aw, don't worry.
噢，别担心。
I see that we understand
each other completely now.
我发现我们明白了
彼此现在完全了。
[panicked screaming]
[clams crunching]
[惊慌尖叫]
[蛤蜊嘎吱作响]
* *
**
No! Bad clam!
不！蛤蜊坏了！
Sorry, sir!
- Blagh.
对不起，先生！
- 布拉。
- What am I going to do?
- 我要做什么？
I can't leave the clams alone.
我不能丢下蛤蜊不管。
They'll just have to go
to work with me.
他们只需要离开
和我一起工作。
Come on, you clams!
[claws squawking]
来吧，蛤蜊们！
[爪子嘎嘎作响]
[whimsical music]
[异想天开的音乐]
* *
**
- [gasps]
- [喘气]
[panicked screaming]
[惊慌尖叫]
No! Not again!
不！不会再有！
I just got clean!
我刚刚干净了！
[panicked screaming]
[惊慌尖叫]
- Remember, no stealing food.
- 记住，不要偷食物。
[consensual caws]
[双方同意的叫声]
- Perch here and be
good clams while I work.
- 栖息于此
我工作时吃蛤蜊很好。
[tense swell]
[panicked screaming]
[紧张膨胀]
[惊慌尖叫]
* *
**
- [yells]
- [大喊]
[clams crunching]
[screaming]
[蛤蜊嘎吱作响]
[尖叫]
* *
**
What the barnacle
is going on here?
什么藤壶
这是怎么回事？
How did all these clams
get inside?
这些蛤蜊是怎么来的
进去吗？
- I couldn't leave them outside.
- 我不能把他们留在外面。
They were stealing
people's Krabby Patties.
他们在偷窃
人们的蟹肉饼。
- Well, what do you think
they're doing in here?
- 嗯，你觉得怎么样
他们在这里做什么？
- Uh, stealing
people's Krabby Patties?
- 呃，偷窃
人们的蟹肉饼？
- And costing me money!
- 还花了我钱！
Now get them out of here, boy!
现在让他们离开这里，孩子！
[clam chirping]
[蛤蜊鸣叫]
Ow!
- Bad clam!
噢！
- 蛤蜊坏了！
Don't spit pearls
at nice Mr. Krabs!
别吐珍珠
在好心的蟹老板那里！
- Pearls?
- 珍珠？
* *
**
Ooh!
哦！
[chuckling]
[轻笑]
- Don't worry, Mr. Krabs.
- 别担心，蟹老板。
I'll get all these clams
out of here right now.
我会得到所有这些蛤蜊
现在就离开这里。
[clam squawks]
[蛤蜊的叫声]
- Not so fast, SpongeBob.
- 别那么快，海绵宝宝。
What's your hurry?
[chuckles]
你急什么？
[笑声]
- Didn't you just tell me
to get the clams out of here
- 你刚才不是告诉我了吗
把蛤蜊带出这里
'cause they're stealing food
from your customers?
因为他们偷食物
来自您的客户？
[claws squawking]
[customers jittering]
[爪子嘎嘎作响]
[顾客紧张]
- Ow! Forget the customers.
- 噢！忘记顾客吧。
If these clams keep
spitting pearls at me,
如果这些蛤蜊保留
向我吐珍珠，
I'll be rich!
我会变得富有！
Good clams.
好蛤蜊。
Good clams! Tee-hee-hee.
好蛤蜊！嘻嘻嘻。
Oh.
[groans]
哦。
[呻吟]
[grunts]
Bad clams!
[咕哝]
蛤蜊坏了！
Stupid clams!
Smelly clams!
愚蠢的蛤蜊！
臭蛤蜊！
Ow! Ow! Ooh!
Ah! Ow! Ow!
噢！噢！哦！
啊!噢！噢！
[enchanting crescendo]
[迷人的渐强]
[chuckles]
[笑声]
- I've gotta get
these clams out of here!
- 我必须得到
这些蛤蜊离开这里！
Follow me, clams.
跟我来吧，蛤蜊。
[clams squawking]
[蛤蜊嘎嘎叫]
- Wait! SpongeBob!
- 等待！海绵宝宝！
Come back with those
crummy clams!
带着那些回来
糟糕的蛤蜊！
* *
**
Whoa!
哇！
- I figured if I tire them out,
maybe they'll behave better.
- 我想如果我把他们累坏了
也许他们会表现得更好。
* *
**
Let's go, clams.
Good boys!
我们走吧，蛤蜊。
好孩子们！
* *
**
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
* *
**
- Are you Steven?
- 你是史蒂文吗？
- [affirmative squawk]
- [肯定的尖叫声]
- Oh, thank goodness!
- 哦，谢天谢地！
I'm so new to this
online dating thing.
我对此很陌生
网上约会的事情。
I'm always afraid
the guy won't show up!
我总是害怕
那家伙不会出现！
- [naughty growl]
- [顽皮的咆哮]
- Oh!
You silver tongued devil you!
- 哦！
你这个三寸不烂之舌的恶魔！
[gasps]
- There you are!
[喘气]
- 你来了！
No dawdling now, come on.
现在不磨蹭了，加油。
- Call me!
- 打电话给我！
[bell ringing]
[铃声响起]
* *
**
[growls]
- [yells]
[咆哮]
- [大喊]
[munches]
- Whoa!
[咀嚼]
- 哇！
* *
**
[all screaming]
[所有人尖叫]
- Hey, there you are.
- 嘿，你来了。
* *
**
No, no pushing!
不，不许推！
We share the swing.
我们一起荡秋千。
Like this.
Just watch.
像这样。
就看吧。
[swing squeaking]
[摇摆吱吱声]
Whee!
哎哟！
Whoo-whoo-whoo-whoo-whoo-whoo!
[giggling]
呼-呼-呼-呼-呼-呼！
[咯咯笑]
- There you are!
- 你来了！
- Oh, hey, Squidward.
- 哦，嘿，章鱼哥。
- Don't,
"Oh, hey, Squidward" me!
- 别，
“哦，嘿，章鱼哥”我！
Not after you lured
these monsters into town.
不是在你引诱之后
这些怪物进城了。
They are a menace to society
and we want them out!
他们对社会构成威胁
我们希望他们离开！
[overlapping chatter]
[重叠的喋喋不休]
- I'm sorry
the clams messed things up,
- 对不起
蛤蜊把事情搞砸了，
but you must remember,
they're wild animals.
但你必须记住，
他们是野生动物。
[menacing growls]
[威胁的咆哮]
- Exactly!
- 确切地！
And wild animals don't belong
in a civilized town!
野生动物不属于
在文明城镇！
[clamoring in agreement]
[大声表示同意]
- Oh, maybe you're right.
- 哦，也许你是对的。
If you really want
the clams gone,
如果你真的想要
蛤蜊不见了，
then I'll lead them out of town.
然后我会带他们出城。
- In that case, let me just
say this from the heart.
- 既然这样，我就
发自内心地说这句话。
Give me more pearls,
you stupid, smelly clams!
给我更多的珍珠，
你这个又蠢又臭的蛤蜊！
[clams squawking]
[蛤蜊嘎嘎叫]
[thuds]
[重击声]
[groaning]
[呻吟]
- Well, then,
I guess this is good-bye.
- 那么，
我想这就是再见了。
[melancholy violin playing]
[忧郁的小提琴演奏]
* *
**
[Tarzan yell]
[泰山大喊]
[imitating clams]
【模仿蛤蜊】
[clams squawking]
[蛤蜊嘎嘎叫]
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
[imitating clams cawing]
【模仿蛤蜊叫声】
[giggling]
[咯咯笑]
[clams cawing]
[蛤蜊叫声]
[panting]
[气喘吁吁]
all: Huh?
[screaming]
全体：啊？
[尖叫]
[cawing]
[slurping]
[啼叫]
[发出声音]
[sea bears growling]
[海熊咆哮]
[panicking cawing]
[惊慌的叫声]
* *
**
[electricity zapping]
[电击]
[thuds]
Oh!
[重击声]
哦！
[whimsical music]
[异想天开的音乐]
- Oh, the life
of a clam is the best!
- 哦，生活
蛤蜊是最好的！
[laughing]
[笑]
[shivering]
Getting cold out.
[发抖]
出去冷了。
Must be fall.
一定是秋天。
[wind howls]
[风嚎]
I hate to say it,
little clams,
我讨厌这么说
小蛤蜊，
but it's time for you all
to fly home to warmer climates.
但现在是你们所有人的时候了
飞回气候温暖的家。
[clams chirping]
[蛤蜊鸣叫]
Don't be sad.
别伤心。
We'll see each other next year.
I promise.
我们明年再见。
我保证。
Now go on.
现在继续。
* *
**
The circle of life.
生活的圈子。
Whelp, guess I should
migrate home, too.
呃，我想我应该
也移民回家吧
* *
**
- Well,
it took me a whole season,
- 嗯，
我花了整整一个赛季的时间
but it's finally clean.
但终于干净了。
* *
**
The clams! They're back!
蛤蜊！他们回来了！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
[splashes]
[飞溅]
- Oh, wait, Squidward.
It's just me!
- 哦，等等，章鱼哥。
这只是我！
* *
**
- [panicked grunts]
Drool pool!
- [惊慌的咕哝声]
口水池！
[screaming]
[尖叫]
- What'd I miss?
- 我错过了什么？
[yelling]
[大喊]
[both shouting and screaming]
[又喊又叫]
- Okay, have fun, you two.
- 好吧，你们两个玩得开心。
* *
**
It sure is nice to be home.
回家真是太好了。
* *
**
[playful ukulele music]
[俏皮的尤克里里音乐]
* *
**